<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Homelab on ryan. himmelwright. net</title>
    <link>http://ryan.himmelwright.net/tags/homelab/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Homelab on ryan. himmelwright. net</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Code released under the Apache 2.0 license.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 26 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://ryan.himmelwright.net/tags/homelab/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Simple Reverse SSH Tunnels</title>
      <link>http://ryan.himmelwright.net/post/simple-reverse-ssh-tunnel/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryan.himmelwright.net/post/simple-reverse-ssh-tunnel/</guid>
      <description>Last week, I was on vacation with my family. While I didn&amp;rsquo;t work a ton on personal projects, I was at least able to spend some time on my TunelBeacon project again. I will write a dedicated post about that project down the road when I am further along. Basically, it will be a simple GUI to create reverse ssh tunnels, that family and friends can startup in order grant me temporary access to their computer when they need support.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Encountered Issues Setting Up Ubiquiti Network</title>
      <link>http://ryan.himmelwright.net/post/issues-setting-up-ubiquiti-network/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryan.himmelwright.net/post/issues-setting-up-ubiquiti-network/</guid>
      <description>This past weekend, I setup my new ubiquiti network. It actually took up a good portion of Sunday, because I ran into a few minor issues. Fortunately/Unfortunately, these issues were mostly because it my first time configuring this type of setup, and there was a lot of trial and error. The basic network is now all configured and has been running great. It was a good day and I learned a lot :).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Home Network Ubiquiti Upgrade</title>
      <link>http://ryan.himmelwright.net/post/upgrading-network-to-ubiquiti/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryan.himmelwright.net/post/upgrading-network-to-ubiquiti/</guid>
      <description>A few weeks ago, I went back to Pennsylvania for a week to attend my college swim team reunion, and my brother&amp;rsquo;s high school graduation. While I was away, the wifi-router Rebecca and I were using decided to die (of course). When I returned, I setup our old router as a temporary fix. It was terrible. So, I began researching how I should upgrade our network. This time around, I am doing this correctly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Updating the Pi Cluster with Ansible</title>
      <link>http://ryan.himmelwright.net/post/updating-pi-cluster-with-ansible/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryan.himmelwright.net/post/updating-pi-cluster-with-ansible/</guid>
      <description>With Ansible configured on the Pi cluster, it is time to have it do something useful. When working with a clustered system, even the simplest tasks become tedious and time consuming. For example, updating the system. While I could manually update each of the 3 pi nodes, it is not scalable to 10 or 30 nodes, let alone hundreds or thousands. Tools like Ansible, make doing tasks such a supdating clustered systems, trivial again.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Configuring Ansible on the Pi Cluster</title>
      <link>http://ryan.himmelwright.net/post/ansible-on-pi-cluster/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryan.himmelwright.net/post/ansible-on-pi-cluster/</guid>
      <description>In my previous post, I pieced together my pi cluster, and installed variations of Ubuntu 16.04 Server on each of its nodes. With the cluster built, I quickly needed an easy way to maintain and interact with the system as a whole. This, is where Ansible comes in. In this post, I will walk through the steps I took to setup Ansible on my Cluster.
Ansible Ansible is an open source, configuration management and automation system.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setting Up My Pi Cluster</title>
      <link>http://ryan.himmelwright.net/post/setting-up-the-pi-cluster/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryan.himmelwright.net/post/setting-up-the-pi-cluster/</guid>
      <description>I have a Raspberry Pi 2, a Raspberry Pi 3, and a Banana Pi. A while ago, I constructed a small tower to house my pi devices. Since then, I have additionally acquired a power source, and some CAT6 cable to connect them all up to a switch. I hope to use the Pis as a mini clustered environment, where I can learn (and play) with some of the &amp;ldquo;Devops&amp;rdquo; technologies/techniques out there.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ZFS Snapshot Backups to an External Drive with LUKS</title>
      <link>http://ryan.himmelwright.net/post/zfs-backups-to-luks-external/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryan.himmelwright.net/post/zfs-backups-to-luks-external/</guid>
      <description>I have been using ZFS data pools to store data on my server for some time now. As great as that is, I am ashamed to admit that I have not had a true backup system in place (raid/mirrors are not backup). I have a backup solution that I have attempted in the past, but ran into an issue and let it drift to the side. That changes now. It&amp;rsquo;s time to revisit my solution, and complete it to the end.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>